Mss.Ms.Coll.151
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Correspondence, general, 1728-1902
  - Townsend Whelan letters, 1839-1845 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - General business, 1840 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Burd, George to Daniel Webster, 1841 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Snowden, Nathaniel to Gen. William Duncan, 1846 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Duncan, William to Rev.N. Snowden, 1846 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Nevins, James to _________, 1847 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Price, Eli K. to Catherine Yeates, 1848 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence, 1848 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - ________ to Judge Hayes (envelope only), 1849 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Brinton, J.A. to Catherine Yeates, 1850 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - General correspondence, 1850 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Nicholas, Sam to Elizabeth Yates, 1852 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - General correspondence, 1852 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, 1856 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Nicholas, Sam to Elizabeth Yates, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - General correspondence, 1859 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Everett, Edward to "Miss Yeates", 1860 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - General correspondence, 1868 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Frazier, W. W. to Jasper Yeates Coyngham, 1873 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Shippen E. W. to Frederick Whelen, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Shippen, E. W. to Frederick Whelen, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - ________ to Alfred Whelen, 1902 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - "Bishop White" to Catherine Yeates, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Yeates, J. to Elizabeth Yeates, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - General correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Series III. Business records, 1744-1856
  Itemized bills of purchase, valuation records, deeds, receipts, records of tuition payments, promissory notes, financial documents, and other materials related to Jasper Yeates’ personal business interests.
  - Account record of John Yeates, 1744 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Deed, 1750 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Purchase receipt (miscellaneous goods), 1759 November 2 - 1760 January 25 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Business payment record for John Powell and James Webb, 1765 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Receipt signed by Joseph Shippen, Jr., 1767 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Receipt signed by Nicholas Waln, 1772 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Promissory note from Lewis Lewis, 1778 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Promissory note from Lewis Lewis, 1778 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Receipt signed by Edward Shippen, Jr., 1781 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Estimate of commissions charged by Tench Cox, 1782 May 11 - 1789 December 10 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Account of Tench Cox to Edward Shippen and Jasper Yeates, 1782 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Records of business with Edward Shippen, Jr., 1782, 1786-1787, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Receipt signed by Edward Shippen, 1784 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Deed, 1784 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Receipt signed by Joseph Shippen, Jr., 1784 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Receipt of goods exchanged between Jasper Yeates and Joseph Shippen, Jr., 1784 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1785 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Receipt signed by Joseph Smith, 1785 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Receipt signed by Thomas Clark, 1786 June 4 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Receipt signed by Joseph Shippen, Jr., 1786 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Receipt signed by Joseph Shippen, Jr., 1786 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1787 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Records of payment signed by Steven Chambers and J. Hubley, 1787-1790 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Calculation of interest owed to "Shippen", 1788 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Business transaction letter, 1788 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Tuition receipt from York Academy to Robert Hetricks, 1788 November 1 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Receipt for taxes paid by Jasper Yeates, 1788 November 3 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1789 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Account receipt, 1789 July 27 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Receipt from Isaac Greenleafe and Nicholas Waln, 1789 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1790 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Tuition receipt, 1790 September 30 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Receipt from W. Hamilton, 1790 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Receipt, 1795 July 15 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Receipt of payment to Charles Smith, 1796 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Receipt for financial exchange to Charles Smith, 1797 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1799 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Receipt from Edward Shippen, 1801 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Receipt for tickets sold for Lancaster street lottery, 1802 September 18 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Toll collection record, 1802 February 22 - 1802 March 7 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Payment receipt from Thomas Vickroy, 1806 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Account of Charles Smith, 1806 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Receipt signed by Charles Rogers, 1812 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Account record, 1815 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Valuation of household furniture", 1815 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous business records, 1817 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Valuation document, 1817 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Receipt of payment from Jasper Yeates estate, 1817 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Receipt of purchase, 1822 June 10 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sarah Burd Yeates estate, 1829 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Note of deposit for Margaret Yeates by William White, 1835 June 12 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Receipt for making cakes signed by Townsend Whelan, 1838 January 19 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Receipt, 1849 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Grain sale receipt from James Siter to A.L. Hays, 1856 May 29 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous business records, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Bill of cash, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Series IV. Court and legal records, 1792-1837
  Court cases and orders, wills, letters of attorney, land deeds, and other material, much (but not all) of it related to Yeates’ professional work as judge and lawyer. Of note are orders to testify at Jasper Yeates’ impeachment trial. Court and legal records also appear in the “Slavery material” series.
  - Land deed, 1752 February 20 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Will of John Yeates, 1755 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Land deed between William Jevon and John Neighly, 1762 March 15 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Marriage certificate, 1785 May (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Land deed between William Hamilton and Jasper Yeates, 1787 December 10 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Letter of attorney for Joseph Burd, 1792; Yeates, Jasper (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Power of attorney letter, 1792 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Letter of attorney for Robert Coleman, 1795 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Note on estates signed by Charles Smith, 1798 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Court orders from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1804; Letters ordering individuals to testify in impeachment trial for Pennsylvania Supreme Court justices. (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania vs. Frederick Beats, Richard North, and John Matthews, 1810 March 29 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - The Academy of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the City of Philadelphia vs. Frederick Beats, Richard North, and John Matthews, 1810 March 29 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The Scots Thistle Society of the City of Philadelphia vs. Frederick Beats, Richard North, and John Matthews, 1810 March (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania, et al. vs. Frederick Beats, Richard North, and John Matthews, 1810 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Land transfer from Yeates family to Elizabeth and Redmond Coyngham, 1818 April 1 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Extract from will of Theodore H. Smith, 1837 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Letter of attorney for Joseph Burd, 1792 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Series V. "Slavery material", 1773-1826
  Opinions, depositions, testimonies, correspondence, business records, and other material related to slavery and the slave trade, primarily in Philadelphia and Lancaster County. Items of note include letters between Jasper Yeates and Joseph Shippen documenting the buying and selling of slaves, Jasper Yeates’ opinions on runaway slave and slave emancipation cases, and John Yeates’ records of his slaves.
  - "Slavery material", 1773-1787; Letters between Jasper Yeates and Joseph Shippen regarding Shippen's acquisition of slaves for Yeates; depositions of court cases regarding fugitive slaves; depositions of court cases regarding slave ownership rights (contested wills). (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Slavery material", 1778-1815 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Slavery material", 1798; Deposition of court case involving slave ownership rights (contested will). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Slavery material", 1810-1826; Letters from John Yeates legally announcing the birth of children born to his slaves. Includes birth dates and names of slaves owned by Yeates. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous material, 1756-1910
  Miscellaneous diplomas, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and other material. Items of note include Jasper Yeates’ certificate of commission to the Pennsylvania Supreme Court, a description of a French and Indian War-era attack on Fort Granville, and material related to Jasper Yeates’ descendants.
  - Description of the attack on Fort Granville, 1756; Statement describing the the Indian attack on Fort Granville in Pennsylvania, 1756, during the French and Indian War. The statement describes the initial siege on the fort; the surrender of the fort's commander, George Woods; Woods' attempted escape from Indian captivity; and the exploits of John Hutchins, a Delaware Indian chief, who helped Woods. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Diploma from the College of Philadelphia, 1761; Diploma earned by Jasper Yeates from the College of Philadelphia. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Certificate of commission to Pennsylvania Supreme Court, 1791 March 21 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Diploma from the University of Pennsylvania, 1792; Diploma earned by John Yeates, son of Jasper Yeates, from the University of Pennsylvania. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper clipping, 1807 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Citizens and Farmers Almanac, 1821 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Rough sketch of tombstone, 1821 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Personal note from Charles McElwee, 1850 January 7 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Pictorial map of centennial exhibition grounds, 1876 September 28; Newspaper clipping from the Philadelphia Inquirer showing a map of the grounds of the 1876 Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Application for membership to the Pennsylvania Society of Sons of the Revolution, 1910 May 9; This application was filled out by William Whelan, requesting membership in teh Pennsylvania Society of the Sons of the Revolution. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous forms, 1752, 1789 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Copy of a journal", undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "To Julia, on Tom's Birthday" (poem), undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Personal reflections of Edward Shippen, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Copy of will of Charles Smith, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Church lottery tickets, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Information about Whelan family (typed), undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Bill letterhead for Dr. Alfred Whelan, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "Occasional Elegy", undated (Box 9, Folder 23)